In the beginning was the Word,
and the Word was with God,
and the Word was God.
The same was in the beginning with God.
All things were made through him.
Without him,
nothing was made that has been made.
In him was life,
and the life was the light of men.
The light shines in the darkness,
and the darkness hasn’t overcome it.
There came a man sent from God,
whose name was John.
The same came as a witness,
that he might testify about the light,
that all might believe through him.
He was not the light,
but was sent that he might testify about the light.
The true light that enlightens everyone was coming into the world.
He was in the world,
and the world was made through him,
and the world didn’t recognize him.
He came to his own,
and those who were his own didn’t receive him.
But as many as received him,
to them he gave the right to become God’s children,
to those who believe in his name:
who were born,
not of blood,
nor of the will of the flesh,
nor of the will of man,
but of God.
The Word became flesh and lived among us.
We saw his glory,
such glory as of the only born Son of the Father,
full of grace and truth.
John testified about him.
He cried out,
saying,
“This was he of whom I said,
‘He who comes after me has surpassed me,
for he was before me.’”
From his fullness we all received grace upon grace.
For the law was given through Moses.
Grace and truth were realized through Jesus Christ.
No one has seen God at any time.
The only born Son,
who is in the bosom of the Father,
has declared him.